mumbaihangout.org 2010-12-22

# MumbaiHangOut

We respect your privacy and we are committed to safeguarding your privacy while online at our site http://mumbaihangout.org. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site. Log Files Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. Newsletter If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter (powered by Feedburner), we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Cookies A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. Our site don’t use cookies. However, Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. Links This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. Advertisers We use outside ad companies to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies and/or web beacons to collect data in the ad serving process and are collected by our ad companies, and we do not have access to this information. We work with the ad companies: Google Adsense, Axill etc. Please check their websites for respective privacy policies. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to·not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy_ads.html). Contact Information If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [admin@mumbaihangout.org](mailto:admin@mumbaihangout.org)  
  
A Christmas Tradition - Vintage Ornaments  
Traditional hand-blown glass Christmas ornaments never seem to go out of style. There is something special about them: pulling them out year after year and smiling at the memories they bring back. Putting up familiar Christmas ornaments is one of the rituals that make the holidays special. This month we'll talk about vintage Christmas ornaments.

Hand-blown or machine-made.

A hand-blown glass ornament is one of the indicators that it may be vintage. However, hand-blown ornaments using vintage molds are still being made today. To find out if an ornament is hand-blown, remove the stem from the base of the ornament. Ornaments that are hand-blown will have an uneven base because it is not possible for a glass blower to make an even break. Machine-made ornaments will have a smooth even base. If an ornament is machine-made, it may not be particularly old.

Big or small.

Early ornaments were smaller than modern ornaments. They were usually done in soft colors with hand painted details. You'll notice that the paint may be faded or distressed in areas on vintage ornaments. Look for round ornaments in a variety of diminutive sizes, reflector ornaments, unusual shapes or ones that represent food. These were the common themes for older ornaments.

Shapes.

Originally ornaments were used to represent the bounty of the year-end harvest with an emphasis on food and natural elements. Bird ornaments represented the biblical messengers that bring God's love and peace to the world. Birds were also symbolic of good luck and good fortune. Fruit and vegetable shapes symbolized the harvest. Pickle shapes signified luck. Fish shapes were an early Christian symbol for Christ. Star shapes represented the Star of Bethlehem. During Victorian times, reflectors ornaments (ornaments with geometric concave indentations), were often called witches eyes and were placed on the Christmas tree to fend off any evil spirits.

Sources for vintage ornaments.

Ebay, antique shops, flea markets, church sales and garage sales are all good hunting grounds for vintage ornaments.

Value.

Prices can vary from $2 to $200 depending on condition and rarity. New or old ornaments made by the German manufacturer Lauscha are highly collectible since the company's recent demise.

Martin Swinton owns Take-A-Boo Emporium located in Toronto, Canada. He has appeared on a variety of television programs; does furniture restoration; caning and rushing repairs; appraisals and has taught courses on antiques at the Learning Annex. Martin can be reached at
